

Subrata Debnath

Date of birth: 01/01/1990 | Nationality: Bangladeshi | Gender: Male | Phone

number: (+880) 1736023940 (Mobile) | Email address: subrata6630@gmail.com

Website: https://subrata6630.github.io/ | LinkedIn:

www.linkdin.com/in/subrata6630 | Whatsapp Messenger: +8801736023940 |

Address: Banchanagor, Jagannath Bhabon, 3700, LAKSHMIPUR SADAR,

Bangladesh (Home)`

About me:

Software engineering graduate with more than 4 years of experience in efficient and large-scale web-based systems development. Highly experienced in backend/REST API development in PHP. Also, have solid frontend development and server administration experience. I love to write clean code and follow best practices. Seeking to move into a new engineering position where I can take on new challenges and excel in my knowledge. Exploring segments of DevOps, React.js, and large-scale application architecture-related skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/07/2018 - CURRENT Dhaka, Bangladesh

WEB DEVELOPER M & H TELECOME LTD

- -Working as the technical lead to develop products and services used by 300k+ consumers.
- -Managing the technical team, architecting the systems, managing the servers, and developing REST APIs and dashboards.
- -Managed, optimized, and updated PHP databases as necessary.
- -Built a School Management software with registration, exam, teacher, and class content management
- -Developed an E-commerce site with font, back and database integration, and purchase processing.
- -Reseller Hosting & Domain Sites maintenance
- -WordPress Website developments
- -Implement a backup & recovery system

01/01/2017 - 01/06/2018 Dhaka, Bangladesh

INTERNSHIP OLIVINE LIMITED

- Developed a couple of REST API services for mobile apps using Lumen serving 100K users.
- Worked on an audio/video calling web app using WebRTC, Vue.js, and Redux
- --WordPress Website developments

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

03/02/2014 - 18/06/2017 Dhaka, Bangladesh

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE Bangladesh University

Address 5/B, Beribandh Main Road, Adabar, Mohammadpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Website https://bu.edu.bd/buPrev/

05/09/2009 - 01/05/2013 Lakshmipur, Bangladesh

DIPLOMA IN ENGINEERING Shyamoli Ideal Engineering College

Address Lakshmipur, Bangladesh | Website https://www.sipi.edu.bd/

13/03/2004 - 01/12/2006 Lakshmipur, Bangladesh

SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE Lakshmipur Adarsha Samad Govt. High School

Address Lakshmipur, Bangladesh

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **BENGALI**Other language(s): **ENGLISH**

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

HONOURS AND AWARDS

08/03/2017

Active citizens youth leadership - British Council

- Develop a strong sense of their own culture and identity through engagement with other cultures
- have increased knowledge and understanding of how their local community works and its links to the rest of the world
- take action to improve society through sustainable initiatives
- work effectively with diverse groups of people
- become skilled in cross-cultural communication and dialogue, and its effective role in community action
- · work together to address global issues.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Traveling

Read Book

Photography

Song

VOLUNTEERING

16/07/2015 - 31/05/2017 Dhaka

Google Developer Group Sonargaon Google Developer Group (GDG) Sonargaon is a community-based focused group for developers on Google and related technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Html5		
CSS3		
PHP		
Mysql		
Laravel Framwork		
MS Office		
REST API		

RECOMMENDATIONS

Md. Sadiq Iqbal Associate Professor & Chairman, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, BU

I would like to use this opportunity to write a letter of recommendation for Subrata Debnath on his graduate school application and I believe that he is a well-qualified candidate for this master's program.

Email <u>sadiq.iqbal@bu.edu.bd</u> | **Phone** (+880) 1755559312

Abu Bakar Siddique Russel Manager, IT at M&H Telecom Ltd

I think Subrata Debnath is a qualified candidate for this master's program because he is an inspiring web developer who has a great deal of passion for the service he offers.

Email abubakar@mnhtel.com | Phone (+880) 1711586277